<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Die martis 4. April. 1648. An ordinance of the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament: for the better payment of tythes and duties to the ministers of the city of London</title>
            <title>Proceedings. 1648-04-04</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1648</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A83160</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E1947A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R231791</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99897488</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99897488</idno>
            <idno type="VID">133262</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A83160)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 133262)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2497:46)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Die martis 4. April. 1648. An ordinance of the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament: for the better payment of tythes and duties to the ministers of the city of London</title>
                  <title>Proceedings. 1648-04-04</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1648]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing (CD-ROM edition).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Parliament --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Tithes --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:133262:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 16 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:133262:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 16 -->
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>Die Martis <hi>4.</hi> April. <hi>1648.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <head>AN ORDINANCE OF THE LORDS and COMMONS Aſſembled in PARLIAMENT: For the better payment of Tythes and Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties to the Miniſters of the City of <hi>London.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>WHereas by an Ordinance of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament of the eighth of <hi>Novemb. Anno. Dom. 1644.</hi> entituled, <hi>An Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance of the Lords and Commons aſſembled in Parliament, for the true payment of Tythes, and other ſuch Duties, according to the Lawes and Cuſtoms of the Realm,</hi> there is a Proviſo, That the ſaid Ordinance, or
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:133262:2"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 17 -->any thing therein contained, ſhall not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to any Tythes, Offerings, Yearly payments, or other Eccleſiaſticall Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, due or to be due for any Houſes, Buildings, or other Hereditaments with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the City of <hi>London,</hi> or the Liberties thereof, which be otherwiſe provided for by Act of Parliament: And whereas ſome doubt and ſcruple hath been made, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the Lord Major of the ſaid City of <hi>London</hi> be ſufficiently authorized to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve ſuch Miniſters within the ſaid City or the Liberties thereof, as have been put into any Benefice or Eccleſiaſticall Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving by way of Sequeſtration by both or either Houſes of Parliament, or by the Committee for Plundered Miniſters, or any other Committee of Parliament; Be it therefore Ordered and Ordained by the Lords and Commons in this preſent Parliament aſſembied, That the ſaid Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſo in the before mentioned Ordinance of the eighth of <hi>Novem. 1644.</hi> be hereby re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pealed and wholly made <hi>null</hi> and void, and that the ſaid Ordinance of the eighth
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:133262:2"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 17 -->of <hi>November 1644.</hi> and the Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance of the ninth of <hi>Auguſt. 1647.</hi> en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tituled, <hi>An additionall Ordinance of the Lords and Commons aſſembled in Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, for the true payment of Tythes and other Duties;</hi> and the Ordinance of the <hi>23.</hi> of <hi>Auguſt, 1647.</hi> entituled, <hi>An Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance for keeping in godly Miniſters, pla<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ced in Livings by authority of Parliament,</hi> and all other Ordinances of Parliament, concerning the payment of Tythes, Rates for Tythes, Rents, or other Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, do extend unto the ſaid City of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>don,</hi> and the Liberties thereof, and be put in execution by the Lord Maior of the ſaid City for the time being; or by any two Iuſtices of Peace within the ſaid City or Liberties thereof, who are hereby authorized and required reſpec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tively, to require and command the ayd of all Conſtables and other Officers, that ſhall be by the ſaid Lord Maior or Iuſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of Peace, as aforeſaid, appointed for their aſſiſtance in the due execution of this Ordinance, as well within their ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verall
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:133262:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 18 -->Pariſhes or Precincts as without, as wel in caſes of Sequeſtration as other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, to all intents and purpoſes, and in the like manner, as in and by the ſaid Ordinances is Ordained, Limited and appointed to be executed and done, in any other place or places within the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of <hi>England</hi> by the reſpective Iuſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of Peace, and other Officers in the ſaid Ordinances mentioned.</p>
            <p>Provided, That this Ordinance, or any thing therein contained, ſhall not be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrued to extend to the payment of any other kinde of Tythes Payments, Rents or Duties, then ſuch as have been paid at any time ſince the beginning of this Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, or two years before.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Joh. Brown Cler. Parliamentorun</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:133262:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 18 -->
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
